so let's speak a little bit about how
所以让我们谈谈如何
hard is it to compute a Nash equilibrium
很难计算纳什均衡
in a normal phone game so let's start
在正常的手机游戏中，让我们开始吧
with a little history jump on diamond
历史悠久的钻石
one of the founders of modern game
现代游戏的创始人之一
theory when he investigated a zero-sum
他研究零和时的理论
game we proved the existence of
游戏证明了存在
equilibrium there and he used what's
在那里平衡，他用了什么
known of the Brauer fixed point theorem
Brauer不动点定理的已知
for that and that's led directly to
为此，这直接导致
algorithms for computing fixed points in
计算定点的算法
such in such linear programs first those
这样的线性程序首先
dancing's algorithms that that really
跳舞的算法
equivalent to what in modern days is
相当于现代
called LP duality and it's an
叫做LP对偶
exponential procedure although it
指数过程，尽管它
practiced used widely of note is the
实践中广泛使用的值得注意的是
shayatin polynomial time approach to
shayatin多项式时间法
solving linear programs although in
解决线性程序，尽管在
truth in practice it's it's not used as
实际情况是，它不被用作
widely as practical procedure and when
在实际操作过程中以及何时
you go beyond zero-sum games
您超越了零和游戏
so when john nash approved the existence
所以当约翰·纳什批准存在时
of a caribbean for more general some
较一般的加勒比
games he use the same fixed point
他使用相同的定点游戏
theorem of Brouwer and that also
布劳威尔定理
informed a series of algorithms and
告知了一系列算法
they're noted there on the slide and we
他们在幻灯片上被注意到，我们
will be looking at two of them the Lemke
会看着他们两个Lemke
houseand algorithm had a much more
houseand算法还有更多
recent algorithm due to Ryan Porter and
由于Ryan Porter和
others I will note that all of these are
其他我会注意到，所有这些都是
exponential in the worst case and I'll
在最坏的情况下是指数的，我会
get back to that later so let's start to
回到稍后再说，让我们开始
the Lemke housen algorithm and let's
Lemke housen算法，让我们
start with a a formulation of the Nash
从纳什公式开始
equilibrium for two-player games it
两人游戏均衡吗
looks it looks as follows
看起来如下
and this is a busy slide but I'll walk
这是一张繁忙的幻灯片，但我会走
you through it and all will become
您通过它，一切都会变成
become clear at heart are two sets of
内心清晰的是两套
variables the esses and the ARS the SS
变量esses和ARS SS
will denote the will capture the mixed
将表示将捕获混合
strategy used by the two players play 1
两个玩家使用的策略玩1
and player 2 s 1 for example of SS 2 K
和播放器2 s 1，例如SS 2 K
for example would be the weight of the
例如将是
probability with which player 2 plays
玩家2玩的概率
action k in in his mixed strategy so the
在他的混合策略中采取行动k
S ones and the s twos are the capture
S和s二是捕获
the mixed strategy of the two players
两种参与者的混合策略
player one player two R's are what are
玩家1玩家2 R是什么
called the slack variables and to
称为松弛变量，并
understand their roles let's look at for
了解他们的角色，让我们来看看
example this equation right there so
这个方程的例子在那里
this applies to any action of player one
这适用于玩家一的任何动作
for any action of player one we look at
对于玩家的任何动作，我们来看一下
the value that it the the the value that
它的价值
they give with respect to the strategy
他们就战略给予
of the on the other player and so we'll
的另一位玩家，所以我们将
look at all the actions available to
查看所有可用的动作
player two we look at the payoff to
玩家二，我们看看收益
player one given that he is playing a
玩家一，因为他正在玩
particular action J and looking at that
动作J，然后看那个
action of player a player of the other
玩家的行为
two and normalizing it by the
两个并通过归一化
probability that the player to attach
玩家依附的可能性
this to that strategy a 2 and so we look
这个策略2
at this sum as a whole this is the
总的来说这就是
expected payoff for player 1
玩家1的预期收益
when playing strategy J given that the
在玩策略J时，
player 2 is playing a certain mixed
玩家2正在玩某种混合游戏
strategy s 2 and it is what it is and in
策略s 2就是它的本质
general if you look at all the actions
一般，如果您查看所有动作
that the player play one plays they will
玩家玩一局，他们将
give different payoffs what we want is
给不同的回报，我们想要的是
for player want to bitch respond to that
玩家想要母狗回应
strategy of player two because in
玩家二的策略，因为
equilibrium every player is best respond
平衡每个球员最好的反应
to the other and so let's call u star 1
对方，所以我们称您为星1
to be the payoff to player 2 to play 1
成为玩家2玩1的回报
in the international Caribbean so in
在国际加勒比海中
general the payoff for player 1 when
一般情况下，玩家1的收益
they play AJ will be no greater than the
他们打AJ不会大于
best response in general be less so
最好的反应通常不那么好
we're gonna add this slack variable as
我们将添加此松弛变量为
it's called that will say is this is how
被称为这将是这样
much pair one is missing relative to
相对于一对缺少很多
their best response or their playing
他们的最佳反应或表现
strategy J those are the slack variables
策略J这些是松弛变量
and so now that will also give us a
所以现在这也将给我们带来
sense for this condition here so the
在这里感觉到这种情况，所以
slack variables are always non-negative
松弛变量始终为非负数
and in a Nash equilibrium they will be
在纳什均衡中，他们将是
exactly zero except when you speak about
完全为零，除非您谈论
strategies that are actually played with
实际使用的策略
zero probability by the player so now we
玩家的零概率，所以现在我们
talk about the SS SS as we said speak
就像我们说的那样谈论SS SS
about the weight in the mixture that
关于混合物的重量
each player gives to their each of their
每个球员给他们每个人
actions in the mixed strategy they play
他们采取的混合策略中的行动
and so when player 1 plays strategy J
所以当玩家1玩策略J时
with nonzero probability it better be
以非零概率更好
the case that his betters best
他最好的情况
responding namely that the slack
回应即是懈怠
variable is 0
变量是0
and when they're playing with zero
当他们玩零时
probability you don't care what the
你不在乎什么的概率
slack variable is because they're not
松弛变量是因为它们不是
playing that strategy at all and you
完全执行该策略，您
capture that by requiring that the
通过要求
product be zero this is exactly the
产品为零，这正是
condition and this is what makes it a
条件，这就是使它成为
linear complementarity that problem so
线性互补就是问题所在
that's clear and you can see now
很清楚，您现在可以看到
similarly for player two for player two
对于第二个玩家，同样适用于第二个玩家
we take each of their actions and we say
我们采取他们的每个行动，然后说
if they're gonna play it with not with
如果他们要与不一起玩
with some probability then and we look
然后有几率，我们看
at their best response here I'm given
他们在这里得到最好的回应
whatever play one is going to play their
不管玩什么都会玩他们的
mixed strategy and we're going to look
混合策略，我们来看看
at the slack variable here and again
一次又一次地在松弛变量处
we're going to require that the product
我们将要求该产品
be 0 in other words the probability that
为0，换句话说，
they play J is nonzero just in case the
他们打J是非零的，以防万一
slack variable is 0 okay so this is the
松弛变量为0好，所以这是
nature of this of this mathematical
这个数学性质
optimization program and of course I
优化程序，当然还有我
forgot to mention but of course we want
忘了提，但我们当然要
the program the S is to be a probability
程序S是一个概率
distribution so they sum to one and
分布，所以它们总和为一
they're all nonzero all right so this is
他们都是非零的，所以这是
our linear commentary program and now
我们的线性评论程序，现在
comma lemke housen who suggests to find
建议找到的逗号lemke housen
a solution in particular way and we
一种特殊的解决方案，我们
won't go over it but the flavor of it is
不会超过它，但它的味道是
to initialize the SS and the r's a
初始化SS和r为a
particular way in fact to artificially
实际上以人为方式的特殊方式
initialize them all to zero and then one
全部初始化为零，然后初始化为一
by one take them it's called a pivoting
一个人把它们称为枢轴
procedure take the an S and an re turn
程序取一个S然后回车
alternating between the two taking them
两者之间交替
out of the set that has
超出了
current value and replacing it with a
当前值并将其替换为
complementary variable if there are
互补变量（如果有）
replacing with an S and with an
替换为S和
information are until you get a new
信息直到您获得新
Caribbean that's the general flavor of
加勒比海的风味
it and in in this lecture we won't go in
它，在本讲座中，我们将不参加
more detail into the Lemke Houseman
Lemke Houseman的更多细节
procedure but it is a procedure that
程序，但这是一个程序
looks very deeply at what a Nash
看着纳什很深
equilibrium is sets us up as a
平衡使我们成为
mathematical program and then searches
数学程序，然后搜索
the space of variables in an informed
知情的变量空间
way let's now look at a very different
现在让我们来看一个非常不同的方式
procedure one that doesn't look in as
一种不作为的程序
much detail at the structure of
在结构上有很多细节
equilibria
均衡
but compensates by by performing
但通过执行来补偿
heuristic search in a certain way so so
以某种方式进行启发式搜索
let's look at it and we'll look at it
我们来看一下，我们来看一下
two stages the first step is to note
两个阶段第一步要注意
that when you fix the support of a
当您修复一个
strategy profile
战略概况
finding out whether there is a Nash
找出是否有纳什
equilibrium with that support is an easy
与该支持保持平衡很容易
problem remember that the support of a
问题请记住，一个
strategy is consist of all the actions
策略是由所有行动组成
to which the player is giving nonzero
玩家给予的非零
probability in that make strategy so
这样的可能性使策略如此
let's look at this formulation let's
让我们来看看这个公式
look and this will be with limited to
外观，这将仅限于
two players and so let's look at they're
两个球员，让我们看看他们
all players in turn for example player 1
所有玩家依次，例如玩家1
and let's look at every action of that
让我们看看它的每个动作
player for example a sub I will be
播放器，例如，我将成为
looking for some mixed strategy P mix
寻找一些混合策略P mix
type 3 profile for one for each of
类型3配置文件，每个配置文件一个
players that will give us a mess and I
那些会让我们一团糟的球员
should premium namely each a trolleybus
应该溢价，即每辆无轨电车
responding and so for all actions in the
因此，对于
support that we're considering we'd want
支持我们正在考虑要
the agent to be best responding so let's
代理商做出最好的回应，所以让我们
assume that the best response value is V
假定最佳响应值为V
sub I does call
子我确实打电话
that number that we want a ight in fact
我们实际上想要的数字
to be a best response to the rest and
是对其他人的最佳回应，
what we want is all other actions in the
我们想要的是
other action knowledge support to give
其他行动知识支持
us a value that's no greater than the
我们的价值不超过
best response and we want it for each
最好的回应，我们希望每个人都能回应
each of the two players and each of
两个玩家各一个
their actions in the support so that
他们的支持行动
make sense and we want these to be a
有道理，我们希望这些成为
probability so we want the probabilities
概率，所以我们需要概率
in the support to be nonzero we want the
在支持为非零的情况下，我们希望
probabilities outside the support to be
支持之外的概率是
zero and we wanted indeed to be a
零，我们确实想成为
probability distribution this all makes
这都使概率分布
sense so this is a linear program it's
所以这是一个线性程序
solvable in polynomial time that is
可在多项式时间内求解
theoretically there's a polynomial time
理论上有一个多项式时间
procedure in practice the procedures
实际程序
used are not polynomial in the worst
在最坏的情况下使用的不是多项式
case but but nonetheless effective by
案件，但尽管如此仍然有效
the way notice that we actually use the
请注意，我们实际上使用了
assumption that we're fixing the support
假设我们正在修复支持
here superficially you might look at and
从表面上看，您可能会看到
say oh I could do the same thing but
说哦，我可以做同样的事情，但是
simply ignore the support part where are
只需忽略支撑部分
we using that really well we're using it
我们使用得很好我们正在使用它
in the assumption that when we're best
假设我们最好的时候
responding inside and don't have a
内心回应，没有
profit profitable deviation we're
利润利润偏差
actually playing these pis with
实际玩这些pi
probability with the positive
正概率
probability because if we playing the
概率，因为如果我们玩
remaining strategy with zero probability
零概率的剩余策略
in fact doesn't matter if we're best
实际上，我们是否最好并不重要
responding at it or not and so this is
是否回应，所以这是
where this assumption is hidden so now
隐藏这个假设的地方，所以现在
we know that when we fix the support we
我们知道，当我们修复支持时，
can solve the question efficiently the
可以有效地解决问题
fly in the ointment is the fact that
美中不足的事实是
there's an X
有一个X
number of supports to explore and this
探索的支持数量
is the second part we need to simply now
是我们现在需要简单的第二部分
start exploring the the set of support
开始探索一套支持
and I won't go into details about how we
我不会详细介绍我们
do it but the basic idea is the
做到这一点，但基本思想是
following we will bias the support to
接下来，我们会将支持偏向
support that are close in size to one
尺寸接近一个的支架
another that is we will not start by
另一个是我们不会开始
considering one agent looking at only
考虑只看一个代理商
two strategies among which his friend
他的朋友的两种策略
he's randomizing and the other agent
他是随机的，另一个特工
looking at 17 strategies we'll look at
看17种策略
strategy profilers similar
策略分析器类似
who support is similar in size we'll
谁的支持量差不多
also start to small supports and
也开始得到小的支持
gradually move to larger supports if we
如果我们逐渐转向更大的支持
do that and we involved and we use
做到这一点，我们参与其中，我们使用
another trick called conditional
另一个叫条件的把戏
domination that is look at certain thing
看某件事的统治
we can ignore along the way then what
我们可以一路上忽略，然后
turns out that although the procedure is
事实证明，虽然程序是
in the worst case exponential as is the
在最坏的情况下，指数是
Lemke Howsam
莱姆·霍萨姆（Lemke Howsam）
in fact it performs in practice quite
实际上，它在实践中的表现相当
well and in fact better than essentially
好，实际上比本质上要好
all other procedures tried including the
所有其他程序都尝试过，包括
the Lemke Hauser
伦克·豪瑟
these procedures do have exponential
这些程序确实具有指数
worst-case and so the question is can we
最坏的情况，所以问题是我们可以
do better
做得更好
are there procedures that are less than
有没有少于
exponential in the worst case and that
在最坏的情况下是指数级的
takes us from the realm of complexity
带我们脱离了复杂性领域
algorithms to the realm of complexity
复杂领域的算法
analysis so let's first remind ourselves
分析，让我们首先提醒自己
a little bit about what conflicts the
关于什么冲突的一点
analysis looks like we're looking at
分析看起来就像我们在看
classes whole classes of problems such
整个问题类
of the class of all games of the problem
问题的所有游戏的类别
of determining a sample Nash equilibrium
样品纳什平衡的过程
of those games and we look at the how
这些游戏，我们看看如何
hard is that class of the whole and so
整个班级很难，所以
here are it's a small part of the
这是它的一小部分
complexity hierarchy
复杂性等级
the class P as it's known is the class
众所周知的P级是
of problem for which a polynomial time
多项式时间的问题
solution is is known the class NP is the
解决方案是已知的NP类是
class of problems for which a class a
一类问题
solution can be verified in polynomial
解决方案可以在多项式中验证
time but not necessarily found in
时间，但不一定在
polynomial time the class NP complete is
NP类完成的多项式时间是
the hardest among all the NP classes
在所有NP类中最困难的
that is the classes to which all NP
那是所有NP的阶级
problems can be reduced and perhaps the
问题可以减少，也许
biggest unsolved problem in theoretical
理论上最大的未解决问题
computer science is the question of
计算机科学是一个问题
whether NP is different from P it's
NP与P是否不同
widely believed to be but has not been
被广泛认为是但尚未被
proved so this is the general background
事实证明，这是一般背景
we need to keep in mind and now we can
我们需要记住，现在我们可以
ask well where does where does the
问好在哪里
problem finding a Nash equilibrium
寻找纳什均衡的问题
reside in P in NP
居住在NP中的P
what can we say well first of all
首先我们能说什么好
strictly speaking we can't quite speak
严格来说，我们不能完全说
about it being in P oh and P because we
关于它在P和P中，因为我们
know from Nash's theorem that a national
从纳什定理知道一个国民
cooter room always exists so the
机房始终存在，因此
question does it exist in Nashville
问题在纳什维尔存在吗
domain is trivial the answer is yes so
域是微不足道的，答案是肯定的，所以
we need to look at a little differently
我们需要换个角度看
one way to look at differently is to ask
一种不同看待的方法是问
for Nash equilibria with specific kind
特定种类的纳什均衡
of properties so for example we can say
属性，例如，我们可以说
does it have unique Nash equilibrium or
它具有独特的纳什均衡或
does a exists in Africa I mean that
在非洲存在吗？我的意思是
strictly Pareto efficient or does is
严格地帕累托有效或确实是
there a Nash equilibria that guarantees
纳什均衡保证了
a given player some minimum payoff or
给定玩家一些最低收益或
can we guarantee some in Assam minimum
我们可以保证最低限度的阿萨姆邦吗
so for welfare in a Nash equilibrium
所以为了纳什均衡中的福利
does the use an experiment I think that
我使用了一个实验
include some pure pure strategy some
包括一些纯粹的纯粹策略
action
行动
the player in it or conversely that does
里面的玩家，或者相反
exclude it all of these and others are
排除所有这些，其他都是
examples of questions that are provably
可证明的问题的例子
NP NP hard okay so that tells us
NP NP很难，这样可以告诉我们
something about the hardness but still
关于硬度的一些东西，但仍然
we still ask about it just finding a
我们仍然问它，只是找到一个
sample Nash equilibrium how hard is that
样本纳什均衡那有多难
so we've seen the algorithm people have
所以我们已经看到人们使用的算法
tried very hard to find algorithms
尽力寻找算法
computing a sample Nash equilibrium and
计算样本纳什均衡，并
it does seem hard the question is can we
问题似乎很难，我们可以
somehow capture that formally within the
以某种方式正式捕获了
complexity hierarchy and and and for
复杂性层次和and and for
that we need to introduce some you know
我们需要介绍一些您知道的
new new concepts the essential concept
新概念新概念
is that of the new class of problems
是新一类问题
called P P ad for polynomial parity
称为PP广告，用于多项式奇偶校验
arguments directed graph introduced by
由参数引入的有向图
christos papadimitriou in 1994 we won't
克里斯托斯·帕帕迪米特里乌（1994）我们不会
go into detail but just so you know the
进行详细介绍，但是只是您知道
chronology P P ad is a specialization of
年表PP广告是
a class called TF NP which is internal
内部称为TF NP的类
with a specialization of a problem
有问题的专业化
called F and P a going detail here is is
称为F和P这里是一个持续的细节
beyond the scope of what we want to
超出了我们想要的范围
speak about but it does help us now
谈论，但它确实对我们有帮助
position the complexity of finding a
定位寻找
sample Nash equilibrium in the complex
络合物中的样品Nash平衡
the hierarchy and again we have the
层次结构，我们再次拥有
class of polynomial time problems of
一类多项式时间问题
problem that can be verified in
可以验证的问题
polynomial time with these being the
多项式时间，这些是
hardest among them and given that p p ad
其中最难的是pp广告
turns out to reside somewhere within
原来是住在里面的某个地方
this class now again we don't know
再次上这堂课，我们不知道
whether this entire clans did not
这整个氏族是否没有
collapse and all become one of the same
崩溃，都成为同一个
it's why do you believe that it does not
这就是为什么您认为它不会
but
但
proof doesn't exist however we do know
证据不存在，但是我们知道
that ppat
那个拍子
lies someplace in between P and NP now
现在位于P和NP之间的某个位置
what does that have to do with the
这与
problem of completing a Nash equilibrium
完成纳什均衡的问题
well that's where the the following
嗯，这是以下内容
theorems come in originally it was shown
定理最初来自它表明
that the problem of computing a Nash
计算纳什的问题
equilibrium is complete for this class P
此类P的平衡是完全的
P ad that is it's the hardest among all
最困难的P广告
problem that class initially proved for
班级最初证明的问题
four players then for all four games
然后四场比赛的四名球员
with three or more players and then
三个或更多玩家，然后
finally in oh six for all class of games
最终在所有游戏中都达到了六分
and so we widely believed that the
因此，我们广泛认为
problem is not polynomial cannot prove
问题不是多项式无法证明
it but we do know where it resides and
它，但我们确实知道它的位置，
within the complexity hierarchy that we
在我们的复杂性层次结构中
are familiar with
熟悉